(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-25T17:10:21.044538",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
君を独り占めしてみたいので
I want to try keeping you all to myself,
今 これから 私が 君に暗示をかける
So right now, I'm going to cast a spell on you.
いい? じゃね 軽く目を閉じてみて
Okay? Well then, gently close your eyes
あたしがいいよって言うまで そのままだよ
and stay like that until I tell you it's okay.
余計な感情(モノ)は 見えなくていい
You don't need to see unnecessary things,
だってだって都合が悪いことだってあるし
because sometimes things are just inconvenient, you know.
口にしちゃいけないことくらい
Things you shouldn't say out loud—
あたしだってちゃんと持ったりするんです
even I know how to keep those to myself.
君を独り占めしてもいいかな
Would it be okay if I kept you all to myself?
ちょっとの間だけ許してほしい
I hope you'll forgive me just for a little while.
まじまじ見つめて しまっているな
I find myself staring at you so intensely
穴が空いちゃうくらい 見ているんです
that I feel like I'm burning a hole right through you.
というわけで 今 君は
So right now,
あたしの目の前に います
you are right here in front of me.
……好き 確認
......Affirming my love,
した 後 曇り後晴れ
after that, cloudy then sunny.
狙って伝えるから 覚悟してて
I'll aim and tell you, so be prepared!
「今言えないのは 負け惜しみ?」
"Is holding back now just sore losing?"
だってだって都合が悪い日だって
Because sometimes days just don't go my way,
今日はあくまで 練習なんです
so today is strictly just practice!
きっとちゃんとうまく言えるようになるんです
I'm sure I'll get better at saying it properly soon.
君を独り占めしてもいいかな
Would it be okay if I kept you all to myself?
常識の範囲 で済ませるから
I'll keep it within reason, I promise.
まさかまさか見つめて しまっているな
To think I'd find myself staring so intently—
穴が空いちゃったら ごめんなさい
I'm so sorry if I burn a hole right through you!
まだ目開けちゃダメだよ 理由なんて聞かないで
Don't open your eyes yet! Don't ask me why.
だってあたし えーっと うまく言えない……
Because I... um, I can't quite say it well......
君を独り占めしてもいいかな
Would it be okay if I kept you all to myself?
ちょっとの間だけ許してほしい
I hope you'll forgive me just for a little while.
君を独り占めしてみたいのです
I want to try keeping you all to myself,
今これからあたしが君に暗示をかける
so right now, I'm going to put a spell on you.
いい? じゃね 軽く目を閉じてみて
Ready? Okay, gently close your eyes for a moment
あたしがいいよって言うまでそのままでいる
and stay just like that until I tell you it's okay.
君を独り占めしてもいいかな
Is it okay if I keep you all to myself?
ちょっとの間だけ許してほしい
I hope you'll forgive me for just a little while.
まじまじ見つめてしまっているな
I've been gazing at you so intensely,
穴が空いちゃうくらい見ているんです
looking at you enough to burn a hole right through.
......好き
...I love you.
いいでしょ今くらい夢見させて
Come on, let me dream just for a little while!
はい! 皆さん、こんばんはー!
Yes! Hello everyone, good evening!
ライブ3期生の白銀ノエルです!
This is Shirogane Noel from Hololive 3rd Gen!
今日は、誕生日の2周年記念ライブに来ていただきありがとうございます!
Thank you so much for coming to my 2nd anniversary live today!
いや、なんかちょっと誕生ね、そう、1曲目からちょっとお疲れモードで
Man, I'm a bit... well, since the first song, I've been in tired mode,
ちょっと息を整えさせてください。はあ、はあ、はあ、はあ、はあ、ふう
so please let me catch my breath. Hah, hah, hah... phew.
大丈夫です。元気になりました!
I'm okay! I've got my energy back!
いや、今日はね、たくさんのゲストさんもあの交えつつ歌って踊って、そしてね、そのゲストさんとたくさんおしゃべりしたり
Today, you know, while mixing in lots of guests, singing and dancing, and chatting a lot with the guests,
おしゃべりしたりMCしたりっていう感じで、あの、楽しいライブにできたらなという感じで思っておりますので
chatting and doing MC stuff—we're hoping to make it a super fun live,
よろしければ最後まで見てくれると嬉しいです。ちなみにハッシュタグなんですけど、ハッシュタグはね
so we'd be super happy if you'd watch all the way to the end. By the way, about the hashtag, the hashtag is...
あの、白銀ノエル2周年記念ライブで、あの、ハッシュタグありますので、そこでね、たくさんマスクショットしたりあと感想をつぶやいてくれると嬉しいです。目指せ!
"Shirogane Noel 2nd Anniversary Live", so please use the hashtag to share lots of screenshots and tweet your impressions! Aim for...
トレンド入り、一位です!
Trending, number one!
一位になりたいです。よろしくお願いします!
I want to be number one! Please support me!
では、ちょっと、早速、あの、ゲストのもとにいきたいと思います。
Well then, let's head over to our guest right away.
で、なんかちょっと、急ぎでちょっと喋りすぎた、やばい、ゲストさん待たせてるから
Man, I talked a bit too fast in a rush—uh-oh, I'm keeping the guest waiting!
じゃあちょっと行ってきます! 行くぞー! ああ、ぶーん! 待っててね、楽しんでね!
Alright, I'm heading over! Let's go! Wheee! Wait for me, have fun!
ガン ガン ガン ガン
Gan, gan, gan, gan!
若い命が真っ赤に燃えて
The flame of youth is burning bright red!
ゲットスパーク 空高く見参 合体 ゲットロボだ
Getter spark! Soaring high through the sky—see the combination, it's Getter Robo!
ガッツ ガッツ ゲット ガッツ! 三つの心がひとつになれば
Guts, guts, getter guts! When three hearts become one,
ひとつの正義は百万パワー 悪を許すな ゲットパンチ
one sense of justice is a million's power—Getter punch against impermissible evil!
ゲット ゲット ゲット ゲットロボ!
Get, get, getter, Getter Robo!
若い怒りが一直線に
A youthful anger is most direct,
ゲットチェンジ ぶちかませ 見参 変幻 ゲットロボだ
Getter change and smash right through it all—see the transformation, it's Getter Robo!
ガッツ ガッツ ゲット ガッツ! 三つの心がひとつになれば
Guts, guts, getter guts! When three hearts become one,
ひとつの勇気は百万パワー 悪を倒すぞ ゲットドリル
one sense of courage is a million's power—Getter drill takes down evil!
ゲット ゲット ゲット ゲットロボ!
Get, get, getter, Getter Robo!
ガン ガン ガン ガン
Gan, gan, gan, gan!
若い希望が虹を描き
A youthful hope paints a rainbow,
ゲットフライト どこまでも 見参 無敵の ゲットロボだ
Getter flight to soaring endlessly—see, it's the undefeatable Getter Robo!
ガッツ ガッツ ゲット ガッツ! 三つの心がひとつになれば
Guts, guts, getter guts! When three hearts become one,
ひとつの理想は百万パワー 悪を滅ぼせ ゲットビーム
one ideal is a million's power—Getter beam, overthrow evil!
ゲット ゲット ゲット ゲットロボ!
Get, get, getter, Getter Robo!
ガン ガン ガン ガン
Gan, gan, gan, gan!
若い希望が虹を描き
A youthful hope paints a rainbow,
ガン ガン ガン ガン
Gan! Gan! Gan! Gan!
若い命が真っ赤に燃えて
The flame of youth burns bright red!
ゲッタースパーク 空高く
Getter spark, soaring high in the sky!
見たか 合体 ゲッターロボだ
Did you see? It combines! Getter Robo!
ガッツ ガッツ ゲッター ガッツ！
Guts! Guts! Getter guts!
みっつの心が ひとつになれば
When three hearts unite into one,
ひとつの正義は 百万パワー
A single justice has a million powers!
悪を許すな ゲッターパンチ
Never forgiving evil, Getter punch!
ゲット ゲット ゲッター ゲッターロボ！
Get! Get! Getter! Getter Robo!
ガン ガン ガン ガン
Gan! Gan! Gan! Gan!
若い希望が 虹を描き
The hope of youth paints a rainbow,
ゲッターフライト どこまでも
Getter flight, soaring endlessly,
見たか 無敵の ゲッターロボだ
Did you see? The invincible Getter Robo!
ガッツ ガッツ ゲッター ガッツ！
Guts! Guts! Getter guts!
みっつの心が ひとつになれば
When three hearts unite into one,
ゲット ゲット ゲッター ゲッターロボ！
Get! Get! Getter! Getter Robo!
疲れた？ 疲れたね。
Are you tired? We're tired.
え、疲れて...？
Eh, are you tired...?
全然！ なんて言ったんですか！
Not at all! What are you saying!
いや今日は、二人先輩来ていただきありがとうございます！
Well today, thank you both seniors for coming!
ノエルちゃん、お、二周年おめでとうございます！
Noel-chan, oh, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you!
呼んでくれて嬉しい！
I'm so happy you invited me!
いや、絶対ね、ころね先輩と歌いたかったなって思ってたんで。
I really wanted to sing with Korone-senpai, so I hoped for this.
歌って踊って。しかもね、ゲッターロボっていうね。
Singing and dancing. Plus, it's Getter Robo.
そう。チョイス。完璧！
That's right. Such a choice. Perfect!
あの時絶対歌いたいなと思って、で、ほら。
I thought I definitely wanted to sing it, and well, look.
ちょっとね、今回こういうステージもご用意しましたと。
We also prepared a stage like this this time.
え、すごい！こんな、こんなとこ初めて来たよ！
Eh, amazing! I've never been to a place like this!
何もねえじゃねえか。
There's nothing here at all.
そう、まさか人生でこんなステージがあったんだと思って。
Yeah, I never thought there'd be a stage like this in my life.
すごいね。
Amazing, right?
これ何に使うの？一応 ゲッター場みたいな...
What is this used for? It's like a Getter arena...
らしいんですけど。骨が当たれ、骨が。
It seems so. Bones are touching, bones.
ちょっと怖いね。どっちが骨になるかと。
That's a bit scary. Wondering which of us becomes bones.
ノエル、ノエル。
Noel, Noel.
あつあつ。
Hot, hot.
ノエル。
Noel.
え、なんかせっかくだからさ、ちょっと一緒にポーズしてさ、写真撮ってほしいな。
Eh, since we're here, let's pose together and take a picture.
写真撮ってほしいです、で。
We want to take a picture, yeah.
はい。やっぱ写真といえば、多分みんなちょっと最初びっくりしたと思うんです。
Yes. When you say photos, everyone was probably a bit surprised at first,
でもやっぱ、ゲッターロボなんなんでね。あの、やっぱこう、パーンと。
but since it's Getter Robo, you know, we gotta go BAM!
いや、ちょっとそれ、やりたいなって。
I wanted to do that, you know.
ちょっと待ってな。待ってて。よしよし。
Wait a minute. Hold on. Okay, okay.
どうしようか。じゃあノエルちゃん前で。
What should we do? Then Noel-chan in front.
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
一緒に。
Together.
よいしょ。じゃあ、いきますね。
Heave-ho. Well then, here we go.
じゃあこの...ちょう！
Then this... cho!
ちゃ！あ、いい！ しょっ、しょっ、飛んでる！
Cha! Ah, nice! Sho, sho, we're flying!
あ、飛んでる！私たち！飛んでる！
Ah, we're flying! Us! We're flying!
でも、なんか後ろのさ、ちょっと感じが、なんだ、レトロだな。
But somehow the background has a retro feel to it.
チープアトモカ... チープアトモカン、いいね。しゅっ、しゅっ。
Cheap atmosphere... cheap atmosphere, nice. Shu, shu.
いや、しゃあ、丸、しゅっ、しゅっ、危ない！
Whoa, circle, shu, shu, dangerous!
いや、今度やられるからさ。
Well, we'll get beaten next time, so.
今度は、パンチで、ジャスティスパンチ！やって、いきます。
Next, with a punch, Justice Punch! Let's do it.
あ、じゃあちょっとジャスティスパンチ感じでいきます。
Ah, then let's go with a Justice Punch vibe.
いいですね。ジャンスね。
Nice. Jazz, right.
ほら、ジャンス！
Look, jazz!
ジャンスー！
Jansu!
撮れました？撮れました？ ちょ、いい感じのとこね。
Did you take it? Did you take it? Make sure it's a good spot.
いい感じのとこ、今ね、スクショしてください。スクショ撮ってから？
A good spot, take a screenshot right now. Did you take a screenshot?
いや。
Yeah.
しゃ...大丈夫？
Sha... Are you okay?
ちょっとね、やっぱジャスティスパンチ、匂いてない、匂いてないよ！
You know, Justice Punch, it doesn't smell, it doesn't smell!
ちょ、ジャスティスパンチをするにはね、やっぱジャスティスの心が必要なんです。
To do a Justice Punch, you need the heart of justice.
そうだね。結構、汗、汗。
That's right. Quite sweaty, sweaty.
まだ大丈夫、まだ残っているんでしょ？
Still okay, there's still some left, right?
まだまだ残っていますよ！実は今回ね、
There's still plenty left! Actually, this time,
まあ、コロネ先輩、1発目なんですよ。コラボ相手。
well, Korone-senpai, it's the first one. Collaboration partner.
え、そうなの？
Eh, really?
そう、で、まだまだいっぱいいるの？
Yeah, and are there still a lot more?
いまして、次はなんと...
There are, and next is...
おかゆ先輩！
Okayu-senpai!
おかゆ、おかゆ、おかゆ、おかゆ...
Okayu, Okayu, Okayu, Okayu...
え、なんかここでもちょっと、あの、見ててもいい前で。
Eh, can we also watch from the front here a bit?
あ、もちろん特等席で見てください！
Ah, of course, please watch from the VIP seats!
やー、じゃあ、まだ、まだ見てよって。
Yay, well, keep watching, they say.
あ、じゃあ、ちょっとここちなんで、ちょっと一緒に行きますか？
Ah, well, since we're here, shall we go together?
行く？ うん、行く？
Go? Yeah, go?
じゃあ、レッツら、ご、次のステージまで行くぞー！
Well then, let's go, to the next stage!
ゲッター・トマホーク！
Getter Tomahawk!
銀河の隅で 惑星はグルグル回る
In a corner of the Milky Way, the planets spin around and round
電波の記録 エコーが返ってきた
A radio wave recording, an echo returned
これで何回だ
How many times does this make it?
遠くの宇宙で あなたに恋をしたんだ
In the distant cosmos, I fell in love with you
届かないこと 理解しているのに
Even though I understand it won't reach
遠くの空で あなたに恋をしたんだ
In the distant sky, I fell in love with you
届かないこと 分かっているのに
Even though I know it won't reach
ああ あなたに会いたいな って気持ちがループする
Ah, "I want to see you" – my feelings loop around
銀河の隅で 惑星はグルグル廻る
In a corner of the galaxy, planets spin round and round
電波の記録 エコーが返ってきた
A radio wave recording, an echo returned
これで何回だ
How many times is this?
遠くの宇宙で あなたに恋をしたんだ
In the distant cosmos, I fell in love with you
届かないこと 理解ってるのに
Even though I know it won't reach
あーあなたに逢いたいなって 気持ちがループ ループする
Ah, "I want to meet you," my feelings loop and loop
頭がどうにかなりそうだ それ以外交わせない
My head is about to snap, I can't think of anything else
あー今すぐ逢いたいなって 来る日もループ ループする
Ah, "I want to meet you right now," the coming days loop and loop
この周回軌道上に あなたがいなくても
Even if you're not on this orbital path
そこに大体、愛があるだけ
There, generally, is just love.
声を辿って 何光年だ
Following your voice, how many light-years is it?
延長線に消えていく
Disappearing along the extension line
このままパッと忘れられたら 楽だろうなあ
If I could just forget you like that, it'd be so easy...
触れられないのに 見えてしまって どうしようもないや
Even though I can't touch you, I see you, nothing I can do
近くて遠いあなただ 分かっているよ
You're so close yet so far, I know that
あーそれでも逢いたいなって 何度もループ ループする
Ah, still "I want to meet you," looping over and over
心があなたで鳴っている それだけが確かだ
My heart is ringing with you, that alone is certain
それだけでいいよ
That's all I need.
あー星が周るように ぼくらはずっとループする
Ah, as the stars spin, we keep looping forever
想いが軌道を描いている あなただけを追うよ
My feelings draw an orbit, chasing only you
あー今すぐ逢いたいなって 命がループ ループする
Ah, "I want to meet you right now," my life loops and loops
この周回軌道上に あなたがいなくても
Even if you're not on this orbital path
それ以外想えない
I can think of nothing else.
あー星が周るように ぼくらはずっとループする
Ah, as the stars spin, we keep looping forever
想いが軌道を描いている
My feelings draw an orbit,
あなただけを追うよ
Chasing only you.
あー今すぐ逢いたいなって
Ah, "I want to meet you right now"
千の命がループ ループする
A thousand lives loop and loop
この周回軌道上に あなたがいなくても
Even if you're not on this orbital path
それ以外想えない
I can think of nothing else.
そこに大体、愛があるだけ
There, generally, is just love.
はあー！
Ahhh!
お疲れ様！来てくれてありがとうございます！
Great job! Thank you so much for coming!
ありがと呼んでくれて
Thanks for having me.
いや、おかゆ先輩とね、だんじゅずっと惑星ループ歌いたくて
Well, I've wanted to sing Planet Loop with Okayu-senpai for a long time.
えー！
Eh?!
っていうのもね、あの、おかゆ先輩の惑星ループがめちゃくちゃ好きで、来てくれてありがとうございます！
Because, um, I love Okayu-senpai's Planet Loop so much, thanks for coming!
ありがたやー！
Thank you so much!
いやまさかさ、のえるちゃんの2周年の記念に呼んでもらえるなんて本当に
I never thought I'd be invited to Noel-chan's 2nd anniversary stream, truly...
ええー！みたいな
Like, "Ehh?!"
いや、なんか本当にちょっと勇気をだしました、本当はね誘ってほしいなと思いつつも
Well, honestly, I had to gather some courage. Actually, while thinking I'd love to be invited...
えー、言ってよ！言ってよ！
Eh, you should've told me! You should've told me!
いや、ありがとうございます！ / いやいや、とんでもございまして
Thank you! / Not at all!
いやだからずっとさ、その、さっきね、ちょっと、まあみんなちょっと気づいたか分からないけど
So for a long time, um, earlier, I don't know if everyone noticed, but...
円になってる時に、そう、だいぶけっこう、けっこうねちょっとちらちらとおかゆ先輩の方見てたんだけど
When we formed a circle, yeah, I kept glancing over at Okayu-senpai's side.
このね、回るっていうのもちょっと実は、おかゆ先輩がね提案してくれて
And this spinning thing was actually proposed by Okayu-senpai!
そう、回りたいなと思って、まわりたいなと思ってね
"Yeah, I wanted to spin around," thinking I want to chase after you.
あの、おかゆ先輩の尻尾を、尻尾をマークしてね
Uh, marking Okayu-senpai's tail!
お互いこうやって、あははは、ふりふりして
We went like this, hahaha, wagging our tails.
でもメスブタお尻にさせるからね、それ、お尻にさして、ちょっととんでもないことに
Well, it makes you stick your butt out, so it becomes something outrageous!
いや来てくれてありがとうございます！ / いやいやとんでもございまして
Thank you so much for coming! / Not at all!
せっかくなでね、ちょっとおかゆ先輩ともなんか写真をって、うん
Since we have the chance, let's take a photo with Okayu-senpai, yeah!
えいっ！ぎゅーっ！やったあー！うわあー！
Yay! Hug! We did it! Wow!
身長差がね、見て、どっしりこに
Look at our height difference, so solid!
年長ちょっと、あの、後輩なのに、のえ姉ちゃんみたい！のえ姉ちゃんだ！
Even though I'm a junior, you're like big sis Noel! It's big sis Noel!
こんな可愛い事言ってくれて嬉しいな！ / ええ、なになになに！え、すごい！
I'm so happy you said something so cute! / Eh, what what what! Amazing!
いや、だんじょちょっと、ジベタ、あの、ジベタ？
Well, Danjo, jigeta (ground), um, jigeta?
あれ好きなんでしょ、その、あの、マリンの、あの、記念かな？あの劇場でその
You like that, right? Like Marine's, um, anniversary? At that theater...
おかゆ先輩みたいな、ねこちゃんがねころがってたやつね！来週ねころがりたいな
Okayu-senpai like a cat rolling around! I want to roll around next week.
で、でも冷たい！ / うわ、冷たーい！ / お腹が冷えちゃう
But it's cold! / Wow, it's cold! / Our stomachs are getting cold!
ねころがり、女子、女子会！あー女子会！
Rolling around, girls, girls' night! Ah, girls' night!
何話す？ / え、好きな食べ物は？ / 好きな食べ物はだんじ、牛丼ですけど先輩は？
What should we talk about? / Eh, favorite food? / Favorite food, Danji, is gyudon, but senpai?
のえるちゃんかな？
Norn-chan, right?
あぁ…
Ah...
こういうとこなんだよな。
This is the kind of place it is, huh?
そういうとこぷ、ぷ、すごいな。プレイ、プレイボーイ猫。
So this is... Playboy Neko.
プレイ猫。
Playboy cat.
プレイ猫だね。ボーイじゃないな。プレイ猫です。あぁ、さすがだなという感じで、なんかあっという間に時間が過ぎていくんですけど。
Playboy cat, right? Not boy. Playboy cat.
実を言うと。
Actually...
団長、この後、あの、なんです。ちょっとまだまだ続くので、あの、お帰り先輩にはね、特等席で。
Um, after this, uh, it's still ongoing, so...
そう、あの、センターにもころね先輩が見てくれてるから、その隣でちょっと見てても、いいですか?
So, uh, Okayu-senpai is watching from Center, so...
わかった！
Okay!
じゃあ、じゃあ、あの、案内します。こっち側に、はい。のえるちゃん、待ってね。
Then, Okayu-chan, wait for me, okay?
待って！
Wait!
ありがとう！バイバーイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
あぁ、行いってしまわれた。
Ah, she went and left me.
いや、なんかすごい、お帰り先輩はね、本当に独特な雰囲気というか、こうペースを持ってて。
Yeah, Okayu-senpai has a really unique atmosphere, and her pace is so relaxed.
団長もね、まったりとしてしまったんですけど。
団長ものんびりしてしまったんですけど。
ちょっとこの後、団長ソロでなんと、なんとね、今通常衣装なんですが
さん、はい！
3, 1!
また始まった 忘れんぼう
It's starting again, I forgot.
手帳の隅っこだって カレンダーにだってマルして置いたのに
Marked it in the corner of the notebook and on the calendar,
どうして怒ってるだとか お分かりですか？
Why are you angry? Do you get it?
謝っても 許してなんかないからね
Even if I apologize, you won't forgive me.
どこにでもあるような どこにもないような シアワセ探しは 始まったばかり
The search for happiness has just begun,
楽しみにしていた プリンだって
Even the pudding I was looking forward to,
君に食べられる為に 生まれたわけじゃなかったのにさ
wasn't born just to be eaten by you!
それ ちょっとだけ ちょうだい
Hey, just a little, just a bit.
ねえ ひと口だけ ちょうだい なんて
Hey, give me a mouthful, just a bit, you say?
あまりにも都合が良すぎじゃないの？
Isn't that a bit too convenient?
飽きちゃったら いらない
If I get tired of it, I don't want it.
残しちゃったら ごめんなさいって
If I leave any, I'm sorry.
…君のせいかしら？
...Is it because of you?
一体全体、私のことをどれくらい愛しているの？って
How much do you love me overall?
言葉じゃなくて形で欲しいのです
I want actions, not just words.
今日が何の日かお忘れですか？
Have you forgotten what today is?
でも誕生日なんて言うのもちょっと照れね
Saying it's my birthday is a bit embarrassing.
結婚するとかしないとか
Like getting married or not,
子供は何人欲しいとか
Or how many children we want.
シアワセ家族計画を掲げる前に
Before bringing up a happiness family plan,
タバコやお酒は控えるとか
Cut back on smoking and drinking,
明日から真面目にやるとか
And starting tomorrow, actually trying your best.
だらだら続いてるじゃん！
You've just been slacking off!
それ ちょっとだけ ちょうだい
Hey, just a little, just a bit.
ねえ ひと口だけ ちょうだい なんて
Hey, give me a mouthful, just a bit, you say?
あまりにも都合が良すぎじゃないの？
Isn't that a bit too convenient?
飽きちゃったら いらない
If I get tired of it, I don't want it.
残しちゃったら ごめんなさいって
If I leave any, I'm sorry.
…君のせいかしら？
...Is it because of you?
ひと口だけ ちょうだい
Give me a mouthful, just a bit.
もうひと口だけ ちょうだい なんて
Give me another mouthful, just a bit.
甘え上手って罪なんじゃないの？
Isn't being good at getting spoiled a sin?
ちょっとだけ ちょうだい
Just a little, just a bit.
ねえ 出来たら全部 ちょうだい なんて
Hey, if I can do it, give me everything, you say?
…君のせいかしら？
...Is it because of you?
…私のせいかしら？
...Is it my fault?
やっぱ 君のせいかしら
It really is because of you.
おしまい！
That's all!
はい！はい、聞いていただきまして、みんな、アイドル衣装の団長です！はい、聞いていただきました。Booo!です。
Hey, everyone, thank you for listening! Yes, you've listened to "Booo!".
いや、この曲ね、すごい可愛いくて、団長も大好きな曲なんですが、やっぱね、ちょっといろんなホロメンがこの曲歌ってて、団長もいつか歌いたいなと思ってたので、この曲歌えてすごく幸せです。
This song is so cute, and it's one of Dancho's favorite songs. I was hoping that various holomem would sing this song someday...
しかも今日はね、なんと、なんと、このステージ、Lunatanaのステージでね、団長歌って踊らせていただきました。いや、すごい、月がある。あれ？月が出てますね、今日。あ、月が綺麗ですね。
And today, guess what? Oh, there's a moon! Oh, the moon is so pretty.
あら、あ、ドキドキ！ちょ、1人だとね、ちょっと、1人は1人で緊張するの。さっきはね、ちょっと、まあ、あのころね先輩とか
A-anx-... Oh, doki-doki! Doing it alone is a bit... Before, you know, we had Korone-senpai and...
先輩とかと歌って踊って、まあそちらもね、めちゃめちゃ緊張したんですけど
Senpai and I, and we sang and danced...
やっぱ1人もやっぱ緊張するなと未だに。
well, one person is still so nerve-wracking, even now.
いや今回ね、ま、2周年のライブということで、
Well, this time, well, it's a 2nd-anniversary live,
ま、2年経ったのにちょっとソロでもときどき緊張タロウなんですが、
so even 2 years later, I still get nervous sometimes going solo.
どうしようかなちょっと、せっかくアイドル衣装なので、ちょっといっぱい見ていただき、
What should I do? Since it's an idol outfit, let's show it off a lot!
リボンもこれ、まあたくさんね、見ていただいてるんで、いると思うんですけど、ちょっと今回ルルナたんのステージでいっぱい見てください。
I'm sure you've all been seeing it a lot, but I'll show it off more on this Lunaltan stage!
なんかお菓子がある。これ食べてもいいのかな？これ
There are some sweets here. Can I eat these?
食べても怒られない？ちょっと、あ、ケーキがある。ちょっとこれ食べちゃお。
Can I eat them without getting in trouble? Oh, there's a cake! Let's eat it!
えい、えい、あ、あ、おいしいな、おいしいな。何してんだろ。
Hey! Yum, yum! So delicious! What am I doing?
や、あ、すごい！あ、すごい！あ、やった！
Whoa, amazing! Whoa, amazing! Yay!
なんかめっちゃ、ドーナツやらマカロンやら降って、う、う、いて、いて、う、埋もれている。
So many donuts and macarons falling down! Ouch, ouch, I'm getting buried!
え、これ天国、パラダイスじゃん。あ、パラダイスあるか。いや幸せだな。
Is this heaven? Can you find paradise here? So happy!
ちょっと待って、今なんか聞こえた？
Wait, what was that sound just now?
あ、待って、団長がちょっとスイーツパラダイスしてる時に、なんと、なんか声が聞こえましたね。
Wait, while Ayame-senpai was doing her sweets paradise, I heard someone's voice!
じゃあ、誰かが呼んでいる声がするので、団長そっちの方に行ってみてみたいと思います！まだまだね、ライブは続きますから、ぜひぜひハッシュタグいっぱいつぶやいて、スクショも撮ってくれると嬉しいです。
So I'll go check it out! The live is still continuing, so please leave lots of hashtag tweets and take screenshots!
では、行ってきます！
Then, I'm heading over!
お、あれ？なんかね、ノエルちゃんと歌う予定だったんですけど
Huh? Wait, I was planning to sing with Noel-chan, but...
あやめ先、あ、ノエルちゃん、あれ、なんか声がすると思ったらあやめ先輩の麗しいアイドル衣装が見えたんで、一緒に来ちゃいました。ピピピピ。
Ayame-senpai's gorgeous idol outfit showed up, so I went along!
本当はノエルちゃーんって声かける予定が、勝手に出てきてくれた。
Actually, I was supposed to call out "Noel-chan!", but she showed up on her own!
あ、ちょっと待って待って待って。の、ノエルちゃーん！あやめ先セー！
Wait, wait, wait! Noel-chan! Ayame-senpai!
ちょっと、あの、興奮してちょっと歩き方忘れてしまった。はい。
I got so excited that I forgot how to walk!
てことでね、一緒に歌っていきましょうか！はい、よろしくお願いします！お願いします！
So, let's sing together! Yes, please!
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promises we exchanged
目線を閉ざし確かめる、押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the overwhelming darkness to move forward
いつになったらなくした未来を私ここでまた見ることができるの？
When will I ever be able to see the lost future from here again?
溢れ出した不安の影を何度も裂いてこの世界歩んでこう
Let's move forward in this world...
とめどなく刻まれた時は今始まり告げ
Time now begins to tick away incessantly
変わらない想いのせ、閉ざされた扉開けよう
Let's open the closed door while carrying our unchanging feelings
目覚めた心は走り出した未来を描くため
My heart awakes in order to depict the future
難しい道で立ち止まっても
Even if I come to a halt on a tough road
空はきれいな青さでいつも待っていてくれるだから怖くない
The beautiful blue sky always waits for me, therefore I'm not afraid
もう何があっても挫けない振り返れば仲間がいて
When I looked back, my friends were there
気がつけば優しく包まれてた
Before I knew it, I was surrounded by kindness
何もかもが歪んだ世界で唯一信じれるここが救いだった
In a world where everything was distorted, this was the only place I could believe in that saved me
喜びも悲しみもわけ合えば強まる想いこの声が届くのならきっと奇跡は起こせるだろう
If this voice reaches you, I'm sure a miracle will happen
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promises we exchanged
目線を閉ざし確かめる、押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the overwhelming darkness to move forward
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promises we exchanged,
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes to be sure.
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the overwhelming darkness and press forward.
いつになってしまった失くした未来を
When did I lose the future we had?
溢れ出た不安の影を何度も裂いて この世界歩んでこう
Tearing through overflowing shadows of anxiety, let's walk through this world.
壊れた世界で彷徨っては足は
In a broken world, wandering, my feet
引き寄せられるようにたどり着いた
arrived as if being drawn in.
目覚めた心は走り出した未来を描くため
My awakened heart began to run to draw the future.
難しい道で立ち止まっても
Even if I stop on a difficult path,
空はきれいな青さでいつも待っていてくれるから怖くない
the sky is always waiting with a beautiful blue, so I'm not afraid.
もう何があってもくじけない
No matter what happens, I won't give up.
ずっと明日待って
Always waiting for tomorrow...
はーい！
Yay!
歌い切ったよー！
We sang it all the way through!
いや、おじ…いや、入れ違いまして。
No, Oji... I mean, we crossed paths.
いや、二周年おめでとうございます！
No, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
そんなお祝いのことは嬉しいです。
I'm so happy about such a celebration.
あやめ先輩とね、歌って踊って、いや、すごく嬉しいです。
Singing and dancing with Ayame-senpai... I'm really happy.
緊張しちゃって、ちょっとドキドキ。
I was so nervous, my heart was pounding.
なんかちょっとあれだよね、バーク以来の…
It's been since the bark...?
そう、バーク、バークの時はね、やっぱこう団長…
Right, bark—at the bark, you know, leader...
あやめ先輩が歌ってる時はこうやって「うわー！」って応援して…
When Ayame-senpai was singing, I'd cheer like 'Wow!'...
逆に団長が歌ってる時は「よーし、うわー！」ってやってたから…
And vice versa when the leader was singing, I'd go 'Alright, wow!'...
やっぱ今回はこう、ステージ一緒でこうやっぱ歌うっていうのがね…
So sharing the stage together and singing this time feels really special...
すごい憧れてたんで、いや、今回一緒に歌えて…
I've always admired it, so I'm so glad we could sing together.
嬉しいです。ドキドキ、ドキドキ。あ、ドキドキドキ…
I'm so happy. My heart is pounding. Ah, pounding...
あ、ちょっといい写真が撮れそう？
Ah, can we take a good photo?
そう、いっぱいスクリーンショットして、ハッシュタグ…
Yes, please take lots of screenshots and use the hashtag...
ぜひぜひぜひぜひ、ツイートしてね！撮ってね！
Please tweet them! Take them!
なんかね、やっぱさ、思ったの、身長差がすごいの、ほんとに。
You know, I realized, the height difference is huge.
あ、ね、なんか思った。よ、要はなんかちょっとちっちゃい…
Ah, right, I thought so too. In short, Ayame is kinda small...
てか、なんかやっぱ、ホロメンね、ちっちゃい子多いけど…
Well, there are a lot of small holomem members, but...
なんか団長お姉ちゃんになっちゃうの、ほんとに！
It makes me feel like big sister Noel, really!
あ、でよーく言うと、あ、ドルイッショがね…
Ah, and speaking of Druissho...
なんか同じタイプの、形が同じだよね？
We have the same type, the same shape, right?
形ですよね。あら、本当にもう、しかも赤と青ってね。
Right shapes. Oh, truly, plus red and blue.
そう、色がね、ツートンで、ペアッショ的なカラーで…
Yeah, the colors are two-tone, pair-like colors...
ちょっといいんじゃないですか？あ、衣装が。いいんじゃないですか？
Isn't it nice? Ah, the outfit. Isn't it nice?
ふりふりふりふり、あ、ちょっと抱きしめてもいいですか？
Frilly frilly... Ah, can I give you a hug?
え、いいですか？え、すごーい！
Eh, is that okay? Eh, amazing!
かんぷく、あ、いい匂いがする！かわいい！
Kanpuku, ah, it smells so good! So cute!
よしよしよしよし、よしよしよしよし、嬉しい、嬉しい。
There, there, there. I'm so happy.
いや、すごい！でもちょっと痛いな、ちょっとの、角が…
Man, amazing! But it hurts a little, the horns...
角のせいで、ちょっと刺さるな、ちょっと血まみれになってしまう。
Because of the horns, it kinda pokes me, I'm getting bloody.
いや、本当に今日はちょっと「コネクト」を一緒に歌わせて…
Seriously, today singing 'Connect' together...
いただき、本当にありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you!
、もうね、大好きな曲なんで、嬉しいです。
It's one of my favorite songs, I'm so happy.
そうですよね、歌ってみたとかでも結構歌ってて…
Right, you sang it in your cover too...
好きなの。だから「コネクト」、あ、あやめ先輩の「コネクト」…
I love it. So 'Connect', ah, Ayame-senpai's 'Connect'...
いや、団長も混ざりたいなと思って、ちょっと今回お邪魔したんですけど…
I wanted to join in too, so I barged in this time...
いや、でもね、2周年の場でいいんですか？
Wait, but is it really okay for your 2nd anniversary?
しみじみ見ておくので
I'll take my time admiring it.
いやいや、もう特等席ね、あるね、後ろとは言わんぞね。
No, no, it's definitely front-row seats, right? I wouldn't call it the back.
あそこ、あそこで。そのセンターで。ぜひぜひ。
Right there, right there. Right in the center. Definitely, definitely.
見てく、サイリウム振ってくるのは。
Look, waving penlights around!
うん、ちょっと！がんばってね！ありがとう！
Yeah, come on! Do your best! Thank you!
いや、ちょっとあやめ先輩も応援してくれてるということで、誕生日も...
Well, Ayame-senpai is cheering me on too, so for my anniversary...
ちょっと次の曲、かなたんと楽しんで歌いたいと思います！
I'm really looking forward to enjoying the next song with Kanata!
伝え合った心の温度を
The warmth of the hearts we shared together,
そっと大事そうに抱え歩いていた
I carried, holding it close as if it were precious.
答えのない願いの中で
Amidst wishes that had no answers,
言葉は未来変えて
words change the future.
幼い頃ずっと夢見ていた私にはまだ遠いけど
Even though it's still far from the me who dreamed of it all through my childhood,
君がいれば少しは強くなれる気がして
if you're here, I feel like I can grow a little stronger.
明日の色を重ね塗った
I layered over the colors of tomorrow.
呼んだ希望辿って止まった世界を超えた
Following the called-out hope, I transcended the stopped world.
諦めない想いいつしか心繋げた
Feelings of never giving up eventually connected our hearts.
泣いていたって笑って明日迎えに行こう
Even if we were crying, let's smile and go greet tomorrow.
決めた誓い辛くて倒れても
Even if the oath we decided is painful and collapses,
君のココロを守るため
in order to protect your heart.
記憶のない時の流れに
In the flow of time without memories,
きっと求めていた温かさはあって
there surely was the warmth I had been seeking.
包まれた瞬間すべての
The moment I was embraced, all
想いは君へ巡る
my thoughts revolve around you.
空に向かって走り手にした
Running toward the sky, I took in my hands
いくつもの尊い光胸にしまって
several precious lights, storing them in my chest.
私の中の輝きに変えて
Turning them into the radiance within me,
迷いを全部払って飛ぼう
letting go of all hesitation, let's fly.
正解の見えない入り組んだ迷路を抜け
Escaping the tangled maze where no correct answer is in sight,
君が流した涙で心目覚めた
my heart awakened by the tears you shed.
そして知った世界はこんなにもまだ綺麗で
And the world I came to know is still so beautiful,
新しい可能性を生むんだろう
it will probably give birth to new possibilities.
時の欠片の願いから
From the wish of a fragment of time,
救い信じ割れた思い
rescued, believed, and shattered feelings...
私が始まりに立って
Standing at the beginning, I
君の笑顔取り戻すよ
will bring back your smile,
真実の奇跡になって
becoming a true miracle.
呼んだ希望辿って止まった世界を超えた
Following the called-out hope, I transcended the stopped world.
諦めない想いいつしか心繋げた
Feelings of never giving up eventually connected our hearts.
泣いていたって笑って明日迎えに行こう
Even if we were crying, let's smile and go greet tomorrow.
決めた誓い辛くて倒れても
Even if the oath we decided is painful and collapses,
君のココロを守るため
in order to protect your heart.
君の側にいよう
I will stay by your side.
はーい！かなたー！
Yay! Kanata!
かなーた！のえる！ふたりで！
Kanata! Noel! Together!
お疲れ様です！お疲れ様です！
Good work! Good work!
ありがとうございます！そしてお呼ばれいただきありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! And thank you for having me!
いやいやいや、今日はちょっとね、お忙しい中来て...
No, no, no, today is a bit, you know, coming all this way...
呼んでいただきありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for having me!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
でもかなたんね、そういつもさ、長...
But Kanata, you know, you always... long...
最近でもかなたんの配信、最近ってか結構前から見てるけど、
Lately, well, I've been watching your streams for quite a while now, but
でもなんかね、そうかなたんの配信お気に入りなんだけど、なんかね、
you know, I really love watching your streams, but you know...
なんか最近肉体タイスるイメージもあるし、マイクらしたり、なんかいろんなこと頑張ってるから大丈夫なんか？
lately you have that muscle image, and you play Minecraft, and you work so hard at all sorts of things, so are you okay?
そう、ほのお忙しくないかなと思って。
Yeah, I thought, aren't you too busy?
いや全然大丈夫ですよ！
No, I'm totally fine!
もうぼくね、やっぱりね、やっぱりあの団長とのね、あの約束...
You know, for me, really... my promise with the danchou...
はやく...
hurry...
このね、あの五時せいちょっと落ち着いたら...、の、見の前にいくそおーっ！
Once things calm down... I'm going right in front of you!
いやあれじゃ、なんかさ、かなたんとこうやってね、まあアイドル衣装を着てさ、こう並んでるけど、
I mean, you know, Kanata and I are wearing idol outfits and standing here side by side,
でもかなたんとね、実は、実は、昔ブルームで、そうMCをね担当したことがあって、
but Kanata and I actually once hosted together for Bloom,
なんか懐かしいなって思いながら、こここう、今グリグリ痛いんだよね、それね。傷がちょっと痛いんだよね。出血するんですけど。
and remembering that, it kind of hurts right now... my wound hurts a little bit, I'm bleeding.
いや、そのかなたんね、ちょっと、まあこう、そん時はね、あんまりこうスクショタイムっていうのがな、ババババって写真撮れなかったの。
Kanata, you know, back then we couldn't take many screenshots during the photo time,
今回ちょっと、写真をね、ちょっといっぱい撮りたいなと思って、で、なんか...
so this time I wanted to take lots of photos, and like...
いや、なんて言うんだろ、ね、やっぱりちょっと、なんかあの二人仲良しみたいな感じながら、撮りたいな。
I mean, what should I say, we want to take them feeling like we're close friends.
じゃあ、そここんな感じで... あれ？あれ？
So, like this... Huh? Huh?
あれ？どこ？あれ？けんかしてね？
Huh? Where? Huh? Are we fighting?
けんかしてね？けんかしてるやつやってるし。めっちゃつらい。
Fighting? We're doing a fighting thing. It's so painful.
え、そんなだよ。骨折れちゃってつらいよ。
Seriously, my bones are broken and it hurts.
やばいやばい、ちょっと、脳みそから違う、血が出てる。
Oh no, wait, blood is coming out of my brain.
いやちょっと、じゃああれだね、ちょっと団長、実はこの負傷したところで、ちょっと団長次があるんだよね。
Well, Danchou, actually right after getting injured here, Danchou has the next thing.
マジで傷も言えぬうちに！傷も言えぬんだからちょっと、じゃあ一緒にさ、ちょっとほっぺうから、バーって、次のステージに行きましょう！
Seriously before even healing! Since my wounds aren't healed, let's go together to the next stage!
じゃあ、行くか。すすす...
Well, let's go. Su...
こんな感じでいいのかな？こんな感じで。じゃあ次も楽しみに...
Is this good? Like this? Looking forward to the next...
ちゃんと準備してくるね！行ってくるで！
I'll prepare properly! I'm going and coming back!
ぼくは帰るね。
I'm going home.
朝起きて 歯を磨いて
Waking up in the morning, brushing my teeth,
あっという間 午後10時
in the blink of an eye, it's 10 pm.
今日も たくさん 笑ったな
Today as well, there was lots of laughter,
たくさん ときめいたな
and lots of excitement.
友達と バカみたいに
Chattering away like idiots
騒いでる ときにも
with friends, even then
チラチラって 目が 合う
our eyes meet for a split second...
…偶然、だよね。
It must be a coincidence, right?
初恋なんて 言えない
I can't say it's "first love"
キャラじゃないんだもんっ！
because it's out-of-character for me!
ねえ あしたも 会えるよね？
Hey, we'll see each other tomorrow, right?
まぶたを 閉じるとね
When I close my eyelids,
キラキラ キミだらけ
all I see is a shining you.
今日も 楽しかったね
Today was fun, too.
あー 恋してんだもん
Ah, I'm in love.
おやすみって メールして
I'm sending an email saying "good night",
返事待ち 一時間
and waiting for the answer, for an hour.
やっぱ脈 ないのかな
Is there a chance for me—or not?
ひたすら 受信ボタン
Nothing but the receive button.
キミのメール 絵文字付き
Your message comes, with an emoji,
ゆらゆら ハートマーク
a swaying heart mark.
期待して いいのかな
Is it alright to hope?
眠れなくなる
I can't sleep anymore.
キミのそばに いると
When I'm by your side,
楽しすぎるんだ
it's just too fun.
ねえ 運命なのかな
Hey, is this fate?
うまれて 初めて
For the first time since I was born,
ふわふわ 恋心
I experienced this light-and-fluffy love.
いつか 言いたいな
Someday I want to tell you,
ねえ 大好きだよ
"Hey, I love you."
もう少しで 朝が来るよ
A little longer and morning will come,
そろそろ 寝なくちゃいけないね
it's about time to sleep, right?
ころんでなくちゃだよね
We've gotta stumble along, right?
また明日ね 電話するよ
Tomorrow again, I'll give you a call,
やっぱ寂しいよ
It's so lonely after all.
もっともっと隣にいたいから
Because I want to be right by your side more and more!
初恋なんて言えない キャラじゃないんだもんね
I can't say it's my first love, it's not my style, you know.
ねえ 明日も会えるよね
Hey, we can meet tomorrow too, right?
まぶたを閉じると キラキラ君だけ
When I close my eyes, it's sparklingly just you.
今日も楽しかったね あー 恋してんだな
Today was fun too, ah, I'm in love.
嬉しいな 嬉しいな 初めてまして恋心
I'm so happy, so happy, nice to meet you, my first romantic feelings.
明日また会えるね おやすみなさい
We can meet again tomorrow, good night.
夢ですぐ会えるね おやすみなさい
We can meet right away in our dreams, good night.
なんかおしりが温かくて寝てしまってたな
My butt felt so warm, I ended up falling asleep.
え、マカロンって、ちなみに月って温かいのかな？
Wait, by the way, is the moon warm?
温かいよね？ 熱いぐらいじゃ...
It's warm, right? Almost hot...
ラミィ来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming, Lamy!
はい、ノエル先輩2周年おめでとうございます！
Yes! Noel-senpai, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary!
あまりね、ちょっと暴れすぎると、このマカロンから落ちてしまうんで
If we go too wild, we might fall off this macaron, so...
このね、ステージは、ルナたんのステージなんだけど、おせわいね、今日いっぱいなってて
This stage is Luna-tan's stage, and Lamy is all over the place today!
可愛い！でもね、マカロンの上に載るのは、今回初めて
So cute! But riding on top of a macaron is a first for us this time.
初めてですね、これラミィも、大丈夫？ ちょっと待って、やめて、やめて！ 私たち土台だからね！
It's a first, Lamy, are you okay? Wait, stop it, stop it! We're the foundation, you know!
大丈夫？ ちょっとお腹壊して、ぽんぽん、ぽんぽん壊してない？ 美味しい、マカロンが初めてのマカロン美味しい
You okay? Did you hurt your tummy? Is first-time macaron delicious?
食べるんだったら、中側がいいかも、ちょっとラミィ、進いっていいですかそれ
If you're gonna eat it, the inside might be good. Lamy, should we go further in?
そう、中側。こっちからだと、ここ掘るからさ、その中！ いや大変だな
Yeah, the inside. From this side, we're digging here, so inside... Man, this is tough.
でも、あれだの、外側、外側ちょっとまた、あ
But the outside, the outside is again, ah—
あの、クリームさ、端、端の方に行って、頑張って落ちないように、落ちないように頑張ってさ、落ちちゃう！
Um, the cream, go toward the edge, do your best not to fall off, work hard not to fall—ah, we're falling!
うわー！危ない！あぶなーい！危なーい！ ファイト！インパルス！
Whoa! Watch out! Dangerous! Dangerous! Fight! Impulse!
何なのでしょう、このステージにちょっと2人ともらしくないファイトを出してしまっているよ
What's this? We're showing a somewhat uncharacteristic "fight" on this stage.
危ない危ない。じゃあちょっと、多分ね、みんなもちょっと急ぎすぎてさ、まだついてきてないよね？
Careful, careful. Well, everyone is probably rushing too much and hasn't caught up yet, right?
多分ね、スクショ撮るタイミングとかもちょっと分かってないから、ちょっと今日はね、ゲストさんにたくさん写真を取る機会をね、ツーショット撮ろうと思って、じゃあここ、せっかくだから
They probably don't know the timing for screenshots yet, so today we want to take lots of photos with our guest—a two-shot! So right here, since we have the chance—
可愛い！手形に。あら、これさっきのね
So cute! In a handprint. Oh, this is from earlier—
え、可愛い！可愛い！いいじゃないの。ぐっ、と、どうです？どうです？これもうスクショはかどっちゃのでは
Ah, so cute! Cute! Isn't this great? How is it? Won't this make screenshotting go super fast?
あれ？でも、やっぱ月のさ、上側に行ってるから、団長、心なしかLamyよりもお姉さんに見える
Huh? But since we're higher up on the moon, Danchou looks a bit more like an older sister than Lamy does.
確かに背が高く見える。ね、一緒なのに、あら、かわいいね
True, she looks taller. Even though we're together, aw, how cute.
よしよし、あ、よしよし、あ、ママ、ママ！
There, there. Ah, there, there. Ah, Mama, Mama!
いやママ、ちょっとLamyもママでしょうが！いやすごい、写真撮った。あとね
Hey Mama, Lamy is Mama too! Wow, we took a picture. And also—
なんかさっき気づいたんだけど、よっこいしょ、しつれいしつれい、よっこいしょ
I just noticed earlier—yo-heave-ho, excuse me, excuse me, yo-heave-ho—
よっこいしょ、見て、ほら！あ、これはブルンブルンブルン！パッカ、バランボード！バランボードみたいでしょ？ブルンブルン！
Look, see! Ah, this is vroom vroom vroom! Like a balance board! Vroom vroom!
多分、ね、ルナたんもこの使われ方は想定しない気がするけど、イエーイ！見てるー？写真撮ってね！ちょっと横からも、こんな感じで
Luna probably didn't expect it to be used this way, but yay! Are you watching? Take pictures! From the side too, just like this—
あ、撮ります。ぶー、イエーイ、イエーイ、ぐーぐーぐー！
Ah, taking it. Vroom, yay, yay, goo-goo-goo!
やばいな、この流れでちょっと、実はね、団長、今回このライブゲストさん、最後なんです。ラミィで。なるほど。ここから団長ね、ソロでちょっとまた頑張るんですけど
Man, in this flow... actually Danchou, you're the final guest for this live stream. With Lamy. I see. From here on, Danchou, you'll be working hard solo again, but—
頑張ってこそ楽しみ。
Working hard makes it fun!
あと特等席で見ててくれ。
And watch from the best seat.
今ね、あのゲストに出てくれた人、あのセンターでみんな見てるんだけど、
Right now, everyone's watching the guest who appeared in the center, but—
あ、じゃあもうここね、ラミィも、そうラミィも一緒に、あ、そこに一緒に見てほしい。
Ah, then right here, Lamy too—yes, Lamy too, together—I want you to watch together over there.
いや、楽しみ！
Yay, I'm looking forward to it!
じゃあ、このこれでいくか。
Well then, shall we go with this?
これでこれでいきますよ。
We'll go with this, with this.
これ後ろに出ててもいいよ、団長一生懸命やるから。一緒にね、ね。
It's fine if you appear behind me, Dancho will do her best. Together, okay?
じゃあ、行くぜ！ぶんぶんぶんぶんぶん、次なんの。
Alright, let's go! Zoom zoom zoom zoom zoom, what's next?
ステージまで行くぜ、ぶんぶんぶんぶんぶーん、わらわらわらわら、ぶん。
Heading to the stage, zoom zoom zoom zoom zoom, swarming swarming, zoom.
ぶるるんぶるるんぶるるんぶるるんぶるるん。
Vroom vroom vroom vroom vroom!
つかず数えて進めばいい
Count to one and keep moving forward
ふたつ数えて休めばいい
Count to two and take a break
みっつ数えて考えりゃいい
Count to three and think it over
マイペースで進めばいい
Just go at your own pace
気が流れ通りの洒落
Flowing with the mood, a witty remark
焦る気持ちを忘れる流れ
A current that makes you forget your haste
無謀な挑戦所詮無駄と言われて諦めることなかれ
Don't give up just because they call reckless challenges useless
オーフェイス 苦しいときにこそ声を
On Face, raise your voice precisely when it's toughest
出して行こう
Let's let it out
オーフェイス 自分を目指してる方へ迎え
On Face, greet the direction you're aiming for
聳え立った大きな壁に恐れることはない
There's nothing to fear in towering giant walls
答えのないこの人生を迷うことなく
Without losing our way in this answerless life
一つ数えて進めばいい
Count to one and keep moving forward
ふたつ数えて休めばいい
Count to two and take a break
みっつ数えて考えりゃいい
Count to three and think it over
マイペースで進めばいい
Just go at your own pace
やばいやばい汗汗マイペースになってなかった汗汗
Oh no oh no, sweat sweat, I wasn't going at my own pace, sweat sweat
また歩くことの本当の理由わからず失う僕らの自由
Losing our freedom without knowing the true reason for walking again
臆病者と呼ばれても一歩譲るそれが勇気
Even if called a coward, yielding a step is true courage
オーフェイス 周りなど気にせず声を
On Face, raise your voice without minding your surroundings
出して行こう
Let's let it out
オーフェイス 自分の目指してる方へ
On Face, toward where you're aiming
迎え 聳え立った大きな壁に恐れることはない
Greet it, there's nothing to fear in towering giant walls
空に描いた未来には
In the future drawn in the sky
今は届かなくてもいつの日にか両手を伸ばし掴みに行こう
Even if it doesn't reach now, someday we'll stretch out our hands and go grab it
マイペースで進めばいい
Just go at your own pace
オーフェイス できるだけ大きな声を
On Face, raise your voice as loud as you can
出してみよう
Let's try shouting it out
オーフェイス 自分が目指してる方へ迎え 聳え立った大きな壁に恐れることはない
On Face, greet the direction you're aiming for, there's nothing to fear in towering giant walls
叶わないと逃げていても変わりはない
Running away saying it won't come true won't change anything
響き渡る始まりの金
The bell of beginnings echoes far and wide
今立ち上がる時
Now is the time to stand up
答えのないこの人生を迷うことなく
Without losing our way in this answerless life
マイペースで進めばいい
Just go at your own pace
ただただ大きく
Simply, greatly
一つ数えて進めばいい ふたつ数えて休めばいい みっつ数えて考えりゃいい マイペースで進めばいい
Count to one and keep moving forward, count to two and take a break, count to three and think it over, just go at your own pace
みんなお待たせー！
Everyone, thanks for waiting!
ちょっと団長アイドル衣装にお着替えしてきました！
Danchou just changed into her idol outfit!
いや今日は2周年ライブいっぱい見てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for watching the 2nd anniversary live today!
ゲストさんにもね出演してくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you to all the guests for appearing as well!
いやもうね、すごい楽しいライブになったんですが、
It turned out to be such a fun live, but...
今回まだね、あと1曲、このアイドル衣装で歌いたい曲があって、
we still have one more song I want to sing in this idol outfit.
あの、団長重大告知と、ま、この配信重大告知ありますよって言ったから、みんなソワソワワクワクしてるんじゃないかなと思います。
So, since I said there would be major announcements from Danchou, I'm sure everyone is all restless and excited.
ちょっとね、団長ね、ま、ちょっとあの、私事になりますが、
Now, this is a personal matter, but...
なんとなんと、歌ってみたも、オリジナル曲も今まで出したことなくて、
believe it or not, I've never released a cover song or an original song before.
あの、団長はね、ま、3期生でも唯一オリジナル曲を出しておらず、
And Danchou is the only one in Gen 3 who hasn't released an original song yet.
もうマリーンにいたっては2曲目入って、やべっ、団長もオリジナル曲出したいなと、いう話をずっとしてたんですけど、
Marine is already on her second song, and I've been saying, "Oh no, I want to release an original song too!"
ま、ここまできたらみんなわかると思いますが、なんとなんと、最後の一曲は団長オリジナル曲を歌わせていただきます！
So by now I think everyone knows, but for our very last song, I will be singing my own original song!
ぱ、ぱ、ぱ、ぱ、ぱ、ぱ、ぱーー！
Yay, yay, yay, yay!
今回ね、なんとオリジナル曲作成していただきました！
This time, an original song was created for me!
で、あの作詞作曲の方なんですけど、あの、まあこのライブを見てたらね、もしかしたら気づいた人は気づいたかもしれません。
And for the lyricist and composer—if you were watching this live, you might have noticed.
あの、CONNECTとLuminusというねとても素敵な曲を作っている渡辺翔さんが今回ほめのびという曲を作ってくれました。本当にありがとうございます！
Shu Watanabe, who makes wonderful songs like CONNECT and Luminus, created this song called "Homenobi" for me. Thank you so much!
団長大好きなね、あの作詞作曲家さんなので本当に嬉しいです。この曲をみんなにね、今ライブを見てるみんなに
Since he's a lyricist and composer Danchou loves so much, I'm truly happy. I want everyone watching this live right now
一番に聴いてほしいので、団長心を込めて歌わせていただきます。
to hear it first, so Danchou will sing it with all her heart.
ま、ここにある通り、このあとね、配信が終わったあとにミュージックビデオが公開されて、そのあと楽曲も配信されますので、
As it says here, right after this stream ends, the music video will be released, and then the song will be distributed,
何卒そちらもよろしくお願いします！
so please check those out as well!
では、2周年ライブありがとうございました！
Well then, thank you so much for the 2nd anniversary live!
これからもたくさん活動頑張っていきますので、よろしくお願いします！では気持ちを込めてオリジナル曲歌わせていただきます。
I'll continue to work hard on my activities, so please look forward to it! Now, with all my heart, I'll sing my original song.
聞いてください、「ほめのび」！
Please listen to "Homenobi"!
なぁにしようか練習中
What should I practice?
しれっとこそっと準備進行
Quietly and secretly making preparations.
心境緊張で焦る
My heart is tense and rushing.
言うんだけどうつよつよありでしょ?
I say that, but being super strong is fine, right?
元気配るから待ってちょっとね
I'll share my energy, so wait a sec.
そうやって成長する子です
That's the kind of kid who grows.
いいかな?
Is that okay?
ほめてほしいな
I want you to praise me.
ほめてくれたら2割増しで頑張る
If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder!
見ててほしいな
I want you to watch me.
ほめちぎられて伸びるタイプです
I'm the type who grows when praised to the max!
なーんにも出てこない
Nothing at all is coming out.
頭ん中真っ白ださっぱりだ
My mind is completely blank and empty.
うんうん、あれ?まぁいっか
Yeah yeah, huh? Well, whatever!
デコボコな情緒を提供中ぽかんとして何しちゃんのこんなが通常のアタシ
Providing bumpy emotions, looking blank, what is this? This is my usual self.
いいでしょ?
Isn't that fine?
それではオッケー
Then that's okay!
1、2、3、落ち着きオッケー
1, 2, 3, calmness is okay!
始めちゃおう
Let's get started!
どうしたらいいのどうすればみんなハッピーで笑顔バッチリ
What should I do so everyone is happy and smiling perfectly?
こっちへどうぞこっちへどうぞ焦らず慌せず並んで合図です
Come on over here, without rushing or panicking, line up for the signal!
聞こえてる？
Can you hear me?
楽しんでる？
Are you having fun?
にゃんにゃんにゃん
Meow, meow, meow
こっちだよ
Over here!
少し眠いの
I'm a little sleepy...
にゃんにゃんにゃん こっちだよ
Meow, meow, meow, over here!
少し眠いの 少し眠いの
I'm a little sleepy, a little sleepy...
また明日ためて寝て 今は熟睡夢を見たいな
Saving up for tomorrow, sleeping soundly, I want a deep sleep dream!
夢を見たいな どうぞくれぐれも あの今後も 褒めて欲しいな
I want to dream. Please, henceforth too, I want you to praise me!
褒めて欲しいな 褒めてくれたら 二割増しで頑張る
I want you to praise me. If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder!
見てて欲しいな 見てて欲しいな 褒めちぎられて伸びるタイプです
I want you to watch me. I'm the type who grows when showered with praise!
またね
See you later!
新衣装お披露目
[New Outfit Reveal]